NARRATOR : For weeks , rumours have spread across Mars .
From outposts to settlements , from town to town .
Something that had been buried for centuries has just been uncovered .
And , as this mysterious force moves across the Southern valley ,
it leaves behind only silence and death .
Take your seats , please .
I just talked with the Cartel .
They 're concerned that the rumours are getting out of control .
They 'd like to make a statement in two hours .
Some of you may not know we 've had another incident .
At 15 : 20 yesterday a freight train , Trans Marineris 74 Yankee ,
returned from the southern valley on auto pilot .
SECURITY OFFICER : Get to your security stations now !
Okay , let 's move !
INQUISITOR : Initial reports indicated it was a ghost train .
It appeared no-one was aboard
until a single survivor was discovered in a rear compartment .
OFFICER : Call for Med-Tech backup .
INQUISITOR : Lieutenant Melanie Ballard .
Second Officer for a squad of escort police .
They were assigned to transfer a prisoner
from the jail at Shining Canyon mine back here to Chryse .
Lieutenant Ballard was taken to hospital under guard .
She had superficial wounds but was in otherwise good physical condition .
However , traces of an illegal substance , tetromonochloride ,
were found in her system .
MEDIC : It 's gonna be all right . Take it easy .
Bring her in , please .
INQUISITOR : Lieutenant Ballard , please be seated .
Do I get a lawyer , or don 't police officers have rights these days ?
Representation by counsel won 't be necessary .
Your rights are protected by the Matronage .
You can speak freely .
- Then I 'm not being charged ? - Sit down , Lieutenant .
This is a discovery hearing , and your presence is required as ranking officer .
I want your ' After Action ' report .
Where 's the rest of your team ? The prisoner you were sent to pick up ?
What happened at Shining Canyon ?
Last Friday at 17 : 50 , we were slamming through a dust storm
on the edge of the southern valley .
74 Yankee was an ore hauler servicing the mines in the outer sector .
My squad was hitching a ride into Shining Canyon .
JERICHO : Hmm , you beat me .
You 've played Tarts before . Nah , I 've never done this .
JERICHO : Let 's spin ' em again . One down and one up .
( TAPPING CARDS )
Fuck me , the Five of Bats .
You 've got the Wheeler . What 's your wager ?
Five bucks .
Helena . Hey ...
Sorry .
Weather station 's tracking a huge storm across the southern sector
and we 're right under it by now .
What 's the mark on it ?
3200 kicks . We should be there by 18 : 00 .
So , erm , just let me know if you need anything .
BRADDOCK : Melanie !
You high ?
Fuck , Helena , it 's just Clear .
I 'll be straighter than this track line before we hit the canyon .
Well , you better be . This prisoner transfer is no sleepwalk .
We 're picking up James Williams .
You mean ' Desolation ' Williams ?
Cooling his heels in the Shining Canyon jail . Deep solitary .
What 's the charge this time ? Murder .
Man 's been up on murder three times . He gets off every time in self defence .
It 's different this time . Sounds like he finally went psycho .
Beaucoup corpses , all mutilated .
Williams shows up at Shining Canyon mine with some bizarre-ass story .
Sends three officers to the medevac before they locked him down .
You startin ' to see the picture ?
And all we got is you , me , this new guy , Jericho , and a couple of rookies ?
BRADDOCK : What do you think of Sergeant Jericho ?
I mean , I was hoping we 'd get a good , solid woman we could count on .
BALLARD : I don 't know . I guess we 'll see .
Well ...
I need you straight , Melanie .
Don 't worry about that , Commander . I 'm as straight as they come .
Such a shame .
Check on our transfer schedule .
McSIMMS : Shining Canyon .
Shining Canyon , this is Trans Marineris 74 Yankee .
They ready for us ?
This storm 's really kicking up a mess . I can 't get through to the tower .
Here 's your coffee , Mr. McSimms , three sugars , two whites , the way you like it .
You want some ? No , thanks .
How long ?
About 40 .
Shining Canyon ?
Shining Canyon , this is Trans Marineris 74 Yankee .
ETA 40 minutes .
Everybody check your equipment . I don 't want any surprises .
Is everything all right , Lieutenant ?
I couldn 't help but notice that charming scene with the Queen Bee .
Yeah , well you know how the service is , Sergeant .
She figures if I want to make Captain , I 'll have to pay the price .
Thing is , I don 't give a damn about wearing another bar .
Yeah , it could be that .
Or maybe she has good taste in women .
Sergeant , you are seriously out of line .
I 'd hate to spoil my record .
All right !
I know you think you 're some pretty tough hombres .
You 've had the best training , you have the best gear .
You probably think this is a routine prisoner transfer .
But that 's what I want to bang into your heads ,
there 's nothing routine about this prisoner .
We 're here to pick up James Desolation ' Williams .
I want y 'all jack-ready and double-tough .
Officers , you can disembark here .
What time 's departure ?
We need at least a half an hour to secure our prisoner .
We got about a four-hour turnaround , and we 're due back at this spot at about
22 : 00 . You can report anytime after that .
See if you can raise the Yard Master , will ya ?
Ed ?
Ed , you out there ?
Rookies , use your breathers .
We not gonna have air like Earth for 10 more years . Let 's go .
BASHIRA : God , I hate this thing . BRADDOCK : You 'll get used to it .
Two years ago we were sill wearing full-face breathers .
BALLARD : Takes about a month to get over the headaches out here .
BASHIRA : So this is Shining Canyon ? God , what a dump !
BALLARD : First time in the boonies , rookie ? JERICHO : Standard layout .
Just another shitty boomtown like all the others .
Seen one you can go home .
BALLARD : You 're always cold , you can 't get a decent shower ,
and they don 't tell you that a one-year contract here
equals two years , Earth time .
Gotta read the fine print .
JERICHO : Where is everybody ?
Yeah , Friday night , the place should be packed .
I mean , a whole 12 hours before sun-up , and there 's money to bum ,
whores to fuck and drugs to take .
Instead we got a graveyard .
Maybe they 're all inside spending their money .
I 'm gonna get us squared away at the rec-fac .
You and Sergeant Jericho go check in at the jail .
BALLARD : Save some hot water for me .
Where were you before Chryse ?
Utopia .
It 's the arse end of the universe .
A penal camp full of work-amnesty cutthroats .
Sounds nasty .
But you seem to be holding together all right .
What you see is nothing .
I have numerous hidden talents .
Need some help with that ?
You 're persistent , aren 't you ?
I 've changed a few minds in my time .
There 's not many of us breeders around .
I 'd hate to miss a chance to give it a go .
What do you say ?
( DOOR OPENS )
Hello !
Anybody here ?
- ( FEEDBACK SCREECH ) - Officer to front desk .
Well , hello Mr. Williams .
No-one seems to be about . What do you make of it ?
I don 't know .
Do you want me to pop the lock and ask the prisoners ?
What do you mean " pop the lock " ? That 's a level-8 security door .
I 've got a mystical way with locks and mechanical objects .
There isn 't machine on Mars that doesn 't love me .
How about we check with the commander first ?
So , what do you do for fun , then ?
Are you a gambler ? No , I 'm short-time , Sergeant .
I believe in saving my money .
Don 't worry about that .
I was gonna do it for free .
Let me put it this way :
Maybe I 'd sleep with you if you were the last man on Earth .
- But we 're not on Earth . - ( MUFFLED EXPLOSION )
JERICHO : That 's a voltage overload , most likely .
Wanna check it out ?
It 's probably nothing .
But , on second thought ...
Police officer . Anybody there ?
Oh , shit !
Jericho !
( SLICING SOUND )
- This is not making me happy . - All right , it 's time to get back-up .
Jesus Christ !
What are you doing ?
I almost killed you .
- What 's going on ? - Rec-fac 's a slaughterhouse .
What ?
" Slaughterhouse " ?
That 's the word Descanso used .
I didn 't see it myself .
According to what Commander Braddock told me
right after we first arrived in Shining Canyon ,
she and the two rookies headed towards the recreation facility .
I 'm gonna get us squared away at the rec-fac .
You and Sergeant Jericho go check in at the jail .
BALLARD : Save some hot water for me .
( WIND HOWLING )
Descanso , sweep left .
Bashira , stick with me .
Bashira !
- ( RADIO WHISTLING ) - Officer to train , do you read ?
The casino , the barracks , the dining hall , the rec centre ...
No-one alive anywhere !
Commander .
What ?
I can 't reach the train .
Well , keep trying .
Whaddya think , how we doing ?
I dunno . This was built to stay locked .
And Williams is still locked up ?
What do you mean ?
He was arrested on suspicion of murdering six rail workers and a payroll courier
up at klick 305 Hub Station .
The bodies were hung and decapitated , just like the bodies found in the rec-fac .
- So how 'd they pin that on ' Desolation ' ? - He showed up with the courier 's payroll .
The cashier realised it was stolen scrip , they made their arrest .
There 's gotta be a day log here somewhere .
Sergeant 's desk .
( RADIO NOISE )
Here .
" Last night the mine called in a work stoppage .
" Reported winds gusting up to 60 knots . "
- 60 ? - That 's what it says .
Anything else ?
" Arrested for theft " Then nothing .
( ELECTRONIC LOCK WHIRRING ) Got it .
What the hell 's going on around here ?
We haven 't had a meal or a piss break in six hours .
Descanso , open the door .
All right , everybody , answer " here " when I call your name .
- Akooshay . - What ?
- Just answer " here " . - Here .
- Zimmerman . - I 'm right in front of you .
Benchley .
Who 's that ?
AKOOSHAY : She showed up last night .
Checked herself in .
Insisted on being locked up here with us .
Well , wake her up , sunshine .
Let 's hear what she has to say .
Hey ! Hey !
Somebody wants to talk to you .
Who are you ? Whit lock .
What are you doing in the holding tank , Whit lock ?
It 's the only safe place at the moment , okay ?
Can I go back to sleep now ? No , you can 't .
I need answers .
What 's going on out there ?
What 's your ID ?
Dr. Arlene Whit lock .
I 'm the Spec Six Science Officer in charge of the mining operation at Drucker 's Ridge .
I left Drucker 's about a week ago by means of a weather balloon I modified .
There was a disturbance in town . It seemed prudent to get out .
Yeah , they said there was some sort of a riot , and the place was destroyed .
Yeah , something like that .
I was adrift for several days . Ran out of food .
I followed the rail road tracks until got here .
Ah , shit !
Then the storm forced me too low .
I hit a windmill and crashed .
And they were kind enough to take me in here .
Well , wasn 't that nice of ' em .
Mel , Jericho , go check out Williams .
See if he knows anything about this .
Williams ?
Do you know what 's going on outside ?
Are you aware of what 's going on outside ?
Let 's go .
This asshole doesn 't know anything , either .
JERICHO : You got some balls calling him an arsehole to his face .
That 's ' Desolation ' Williams .
I heard he took out at least six when they cornered him at Denos Station .
Yeah , and this is eight inches .
You men love to exaggerate , Jericho .
Just goes with the territory .
Yeah , well , in my case it 's a bit different .
Perhaps a connoisseur like yourself
would appreciate what I have to offer .
( MUFFLED BANGING )
( MUFFLED BANGING PERSISTS )
( BANGING CONTINUES )
BALLARD : Go get the commander .
Disarm her .
Officer !
BALLARD : It was almost like she was ...
possessed .
Like there was some kind of force inside her .
Who was she ?
She was a dispatch officer .
We tried to make her comfortable .
The rookies took her to a storage room in the back of the jail .
And then the commander and I went back outside to look around town .
- What do you think ? - That the Science Officer is lying .
- Tell me again about Williams . - I didn 't read the full file .
Caught him with the money , but he said he didn 't kill anybody .
- Of course , they all just died of fright ! - And then cut their own heads off ?
( WIND WHISTLING )
MAN : ( SCREAMING ) No !
Put down your weapon ! Put it down !
Call Jericho .
Sergeant Jericho , we need back-up !
We 're 20 southwest of the rec-fac .
MAN : Don 't open the door ! Don 't let it out !
Who goes there ?
MAN : Can 't fight it ! It 's in me !
Commander Braddock !
There 's a man in there . Open it .
The lock is destroyed , we 're gonna need a cutting torch .
- How long ? - At least half an hour , maybe more .
What the fuck is going on here , Lieutenant ?
He committed suicide .
But , before he slit his throat , he yelled something . Something like ,
" Stay away ! "
" Don 't open the door . "
" Stay away . "
And now the commander 's gone .
Helena !
Maybe he was contagious ?
Or crazy , I dunno .
I say we take him at his word and leave him locked in .
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
Look , one of us has to stay with the rookies .
Why don 't you go back to the jail ? I 'll find the commander .
Let 's get the hell outta this place .
Nothing we can do for this guy .
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
You 're right .
Okay , let 's go .
Drop your weapon , or I cut this dyke-bitch head off !
What the fuck happened ? !
Bashira let him out for some food .
Let me guess , you unshackled him ?
What do you want , Williams ?
I wanna get the fuck outta here !
Okay . We 'll let you walk , just let the girl go .
You think I 'm falling for that shit ?
I can 't let you take the rookie .
Take me .
Okay ?
Put the gun down !
Put ' em down !
Drop your gun , Descanso .
Yeah , drop the gun , Descanso .
BALLARD : Relax ! Relax ! Take it easy , take it easy .
Relax ! Relax .
You 're gonna get what you want .
I know I 'm gonna get everythin ' I want . Now let 's go .
Damn , girl . I like you already .
Shit .
You okay ?
Just swell .
Where 's Williams ?
He took off out the airlock .
He ran into the clinic . I saw him go in not even two minutes ago .
Let me guess , he 's got your shotgun ? Couldn 't help it , he was too fast .
He 's still in there . I can see the back door from here .
BALLARD : All right , you two take the back door .
I 'll go in the front and flush him out . If he comes at you , shoot to kill .
Hey .
( RASPING SOUND )
( SNARLING )
Now what ?
( SCREAMING )
How the hell 'd that happen ?
- Let 's go . - Wait a minute .
Looks like you 're coming with me now .
You see what 's going on out there .
You know I didn 't kill nobody .
I said , move it .
I ain 't going nowhere .
I just saved your life ! You should let me go .
And I saved yours . Looks like we 're even .
- ( COCKING SHOTGUN ) - Now move it !
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
( DOOR SLAMS )
Let me ask you something , ' Desolation ' .
If you 're so innocent , how come we found stolen flash on you ?
I didn 't say I was innocent .
I said I didn 't kill nobody .
Okay , let 's say I believe you .
What exactly happened at K-305 ?
I don 't know . I was just changing trains from Camp Sinai .
Had a little time to get me something to eat .
( COCKING SHOTGUN )
So I went into the station .
BALLARD : It was just lying there , so you took it ?
You would have done the same thing .
See , that 's where you 're wrong .
I 'm a cop , not a crook .
It 's a thin line between a cop and a crook these days .
You think it 's a big difference between you and me ?
You just got The Woman behind your bullshit .
Look at you .
You look high right now .
You know I saved your life out there .
So why don 't you save mine , and let me outta here ?
Look ...
My job is to bring you back to Chryse to stand trial .
I don 't think you did it .
But that 's not my call .
So let 's not make this any more complicated than it has to be .
WILLIAMS : It 's gonna be real complicated .
Believe that shit .
Ain 't going back !
So , you secured your prisoner .
Where was your commanding officer during this time ?
Well , I can only report what Sergeant Jericho told me later .
After the man in the robot committed suicide ,
Jericho went looking for the commander .
Let 's get the hell out of this place .
There 's othing we can do for this guy .
Yeah .
You 're right .
Let 's go .
Commander Braddock !
( PANTING )
( SCREAMING )
( GRUNTING ) ( FLESH TEARING )
- ( DIGGING SOUND ) - ( GRUNTING )
( ROARING )
( TRIBAL CHANTING )
( SHOUTING IN MARTIAN )
- ( FLESH SLICING ) - ( CROWD CHEERING )
( CHANTING )
( ROARING )
( FLESH SLICING )
( SHOUTING IN MARTIAN )
( CROWD CHEERING )
Lieutenant . We got a situation here .
Sergeant , you 're breaking up . I can hardly hear you .
The commander 's dead . ( RADIO STATIC )
JERICHO : Everybody in the mine 's gone insane .
- Jericho , can you read ? - ( RADIO STATIC )
- Jericho ! - ( RADIO STATIC )
( WHITLOCK LAUGHING )
PRISONER : Hey , come on . Let us outta here .
- Start at the beginning ! - Oh ! ( LAUGHING )
I told you I got here last night . Don 't bullshit me !
BASHIRA : Lieutenant !
Okay .
What the hell is going on out there ?
What ?
In semi-arid regions on Earth , there are certain organisms
that live in small pools that are formed by the annual rains .
When the pools dry up , those organisms can 't live ,
but they don 't die , either , they go dormant .
Below the surface , away from the hot sun
until the next rain cycle begins .
Then they re-emerge . I think something like that 's happening here .
I don 't understand .
Well , whatever used to live here , we woke it up .
It takes us , okay ?
I 'm talking about a kind of possession .
DESCANSO : Lieutenant , Sergeant Jericho 's on the radio .
He said he found three people out there .
They 're on the way with an ETA of 5 minutes .
I think you should get on the radio and talk to him .
BALLARD : What do you mean he 's found three people ?
DESCANSO : That 's what he said .
( ROARING )
( CATTLE PROD SPARKS )
( CATTLE PROD SIZZLES )
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
BALLARD : You okay ? WHITLOCK : No .
Is something broken ?
No , I 'm all right .
But it 's out of the body now .
Yeah , it 's loose in here .
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
Lieutenant , Sergeant 's on the radio .
( GHOSTLY RASPING INTENSIFIES )
JERICHO : Lieutenant , We 're coming in . Can you read me ?
Sergeant , where are you ?
We 're right down the street .
" We " ? Who 's " we " ?
I found three people alive out here . Come on , open the door for us .
JERICHO : I 've been trying to reach you on the radio .
Just you make sure that door is locked .
There must be 200 of them fucking freaks
and any minute now , they 're gonna come and kick our arse .
OK . Relax .
Who are these guys ?
I found them hidin ' up in the mine shed .
Lieutenant , we got a situation here .
Sergeant , you 're breaking up . I can hardly hear you .
The commander 's dead .
And everybody in the mine 's gone insane .
UNO : Check the window !
TRES : They didn 't see . They 're going .
Who are you ?
Who are we ? Who are you ?
The man asked you a question .
My name 's Jericho .
At least he 's not one of them .
What 's happening out there ?
Who the fuck are those clowns ?
What are they all sparked-up about ?
Used to be miners . Then everybody in this place lost their mind .
Running around , chopping people 's heads off .
Ease up , man .
We were on the rim when they called the work stoppage .
( INDISTINCT SHOUTING )
- What are they doing ? - Shit , I don 't know .
TRES : Look at that , they 're knocking off early for the night .
How we gonna sneak in , if they knock off early for the night ?
Shut up ! What the hell is that ?
( DISTANT CRIES )
Let 's get the hell outta here .
We hid till the storm was over .
Later , I went out to take a look around .
Thought they were all dead .
Then some of them started to come to .
They walked around like they were confused or lost .
A few of them seemed okay . They tried to help the others .
- Then they started changing . - Changing ? What do you mean ?
They act different , stand different .
Start cutting themselves for decoration .
Filing their teeth .
Making weapons .
( DISTANT SCREAMS )
Killing ones who hadn 't changed .
Argh !
- Cutting people 's faces off . - ( FLESH SLICING )
Wearing ' em for masks .
You lads got any weapons ?
I mean real weapons .
Only cops can have guns .
Some detonators in them cases over there .
Do you know how these things work ?
I know you need dynamite to use ' em .
Okay , then . We take our prisoner and we all get on the train .
What prisoner would that be ?
That doesn 't concern you .
If it 's ' Desolation ' Williams
it concerns me very much .
Now , drop your weapon .
All o ' you ! Weapons on the floor .
So only cops have guns , eh ? You fucking pricks .
We lied . Now go get Williams .
I don 't think so .
What was that ?
Fucking kill me .
No problem .
Will you two stop fucking about ?
Lieutenant , let Williams out .
Give me one good reason .
I just gave you about 200 good reasons .
And they 're probably outside right now .
It doesn 't matter that Williams is wanted for murder ,
And it doesn 't matter that this lot are scumbags .
What matters right now is that we stick together to get out of here .
All of us .
Including Williams .
Including them .
Who are you calling scumbag , motherfucker ?
Now quit with all your fuckin ' stalling and take us to Williams !
WILLIAMS : I 'll be goddamned !
Whoo !
Finally ...
Man , this town done went crazy .
We had to improvise . You like it ?
Love it .
I want you to let him out .
Wassup , D ?
I 'm still shackled .
You pigs on a fucking break ? Free him up !
I knew you 'd let me go .
- Been a long time . - I didn 't think y 'all could do it .
Piece o ' cake !
It was my plan , ' Desolation ' .
( CELL DOOR LOCKS )
Fuck !
- Thought you was watchin ' the door . - Was !
Bitch , you better open this door !
I don 't think so .
You don 't open that door , I 'm gonna blow your head off .
Then your asses 'll never get out .
Someone 'll find you guys sometime tied upside down with your heads cut off .
Tell your dogs to quit barking so we can talk .
Put ' em down .
Put it down .
Listen to me , Williams . We don 't have a lot of time .
You need us and we need you .
We 've all seen what 's going on out there .
And none of us is going to survive if we don 't stick together .
I need you to give me your word that if I open this door
you and your boys will stand by my command at all times .
I never give my word .
It 's okay .
I never make deals with criminals , either .
You got it .
What ? Oh , no . You 're making deals with cops ?
And you are , too . Give her your weapon .
Everybody , give it up .
Well , introduce us to your friends .
These are my compadres .
Uno , Dos and Tres .
Uno must be the nice one .
You got that right , butchie .
I 'm not as nice as ' Desolation ' and I 'll cut your fuckin ' titties off .
Who 's in charge here ?
You better let go of my arm .
- Who is in charge here ? - You ! You !
Shit ! You ! You ! You !
Shit !
You just gonna stand there and watch her break my shit ?
Yeah .
And now that you 're done mopping the floor , why don 't you get me a beer , killer .
All right , what 's next ?
We get more deputies .
You 're deputised .
Consider this a martial law situation .
Let 's go .
( RASPING )
When did this start ?
It started a few minutes ago .
- What should we do with him ? - We can 't take him with us .
Then here he stays .
( INHALING DEEPLY )
Guys , what is that ?
It 's a ' Laffer ' , a black-market breather .
- It has a 15 % nitrous mix . - Gets you high ?
Turns your brain into Swiss cheese .
One gross of detonators . What are those good for ?
It would help if we had some dynamite , but they make a pretty good bang .
We could put them in some food cans or something , make hand grenades .
All right , you got 10 minutes .
Easy .
Here , let me do it .
( INHALES DEEPLY )
( UNO LAUGHING )
That 's beautiful !
That 's what you get , dumb-ass .
You gonna be okay to do this ?
( STAMMERING ) No problema .
All right , it 's almost 22 : 00 hours . Here 's the plan . Short and simple .
Descanso and Jericho take the lead , everybody else follows .
It 's 50 metres from here to the station . Bashira and I are in the rear .
Any questions ?
Hey !
Put your hand down .
All clear .
Lets do it !
Hey , bro , I don 't see no motherfuckin ' train .
Hey , lady .
We don 't see no train .
It 'll be here .
All right , come on . Go !
( EXPLOSIONS )
That 's the mine office !
What the hell are they doin ' ?
Tearin ' the whole town apart , building by building .
BALLARD : Come on , pick it up !
( GROWLING )
JERICHO : Lieutenant !
BALLARD : Hold your fire . Just keep on moving .
Go !
- Where 's the train ? - I dunno .
You don 't know ? What the fuck is that supposed to mean ?
Lieutenant Ballard to the train . Come in .
Plan A is fucked up . You got a Plan B ?
Yeah . It 's the same as Plan A. You got any fresh ideas ?
Yeah , what we shoulda done in the first place .
Shit !
Come on , you mindless motherfuckers !
- The second time I saved your life . - Yeah , run a tab !
UNO : Jericho ! Grenade !
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
Come on , man , on your feet . Let 's move !
Shit .
( LEADER SHOUTING IN MARTIAN )
( HORDE ROARING )
( GROWLING )
Hey ! Open that door !
BALLARD : We sealed the airlock doors and Sergeant Jericho dismantled the lock .
They couldn 't open the door from outside , so we were safe
for a while .
Get on the radio . Try to reach the train .
TRES : Where 's your brother ?
He didn 't make it .
Oh , God .
Uno was your brother ?
Yeah .
( LEADER ROARING )
( TRIBAL CHANTING )
Look at him .
Whatever 's inside of him has waited a long time to get out .
I didn 't understand their design , how they move .
It 's gotta be the wind .
Yeah , the wind takes them .
Once the host dies , they drift along from town to town , human to human .
What a perfect creation .
Vengeance on anything or anyone that tries to lay claim to their planet .
( SNARLS )
What did you see at Drucker 's Ridge ?
I was at the mine when they called a work stoppage .
There was a section 740 , a scientifically significant find .
( EXPLOSION )
A 740 applies to any number of things found on Mars .
A biological organism , an indication of water , things like that .
After we dynamited the mountain , we discovered an entrance .
It was a tunnel carved into the rock .
It had been hidden underneath the outer walls for centuries
and someone other than man had carved it
( THUNDERING SOUND )
WHITLOCK : Jesus !
MINER : What the hell is that ? WHITLOCK : I don 't know .
( SCREECHING SOUNDS )
MINER : Get the hell out of here !
It was me .
I opened Pandora 's box . I let ' em out .
BASHIRA : I made contact with the train .
They 're about three klicks north of town on a decoupling spur .
- They said the tracks are blocked . - Can they get through ?
Yeah , they 're working on it .
( PRISONER ROARS )
- You okay ? - Yes .
- Barricaded the rear door . - Good .
There 's a maintenance courtyard out back enclosed by a five metre wall .
There 's even a Rover parked out there . Maybe we can make a run for it .
No , we wait .
Bashira got in touch with the train . They 're coming back for us .
( EXPLOSIONS )
( HORDE CHEERING )
Well , if a train coming , they 'd better hurry up .
What 's the matter with you ? You did good out there .
Yeah , right .
It 's a fucked-up situation .
I never put too much faith in cops , but you did all right .
You trust me ?
Hell , no .
You know , I really don 't understand you at all , ' Desolation ' .
- Only one lookin ' out for me is me . - Doesn 't that bother you ?
Nothing bothers me .
I stopped worrying a long time ago .
Don 't you believe in anything ?
I believe in stayin ' alive .
Yeah , but for what ?
Stick around , I might let you know one day .
When ?
When the tide is high and the water 's rising .
Doing okay in here ?
Mel .
Check this out .
What about it ?
It 's pretty solid .
One way in , and a back door out , leading to the rear entrance .
A good , sturdy door .
So , what 's your point ?
It 's rather cosy , don 't you think ?
I don 't believe this . You lured me here to seduce me ?
Well , the way things are going
I thought this might be our last chance to , er
to dance .
Yeah .
( MUFFLED GUNFIRE )
BASHIRA : Fuck him , whatever the fuck he is .
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
It 's out .
- ( GHOSTLY RASPING ) - Everyone go , now !
Let 's take her out back .
What the fuck do you mean ? We ain 't moving her anywhere .
It 's taken her over , man . There 's nothing we can do .
Easy , man , lost a brother in this .
That 's not her .
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
Come on .
( RASPING CONTINUES )
WILLIAMS : Let 's put her down , before they hear us .
This belongs to her .
- Where did you get it ? - I stole it .
Do you know what it is ?
It 's her stash .
This will mess with anything in there .
Bon voyage , Mel .
Come on , let 's get the hell back in here .
( DOOR BANGS SHUT )
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
( GASPING )
( WIND HOWLING )
No ...
I will not !
I was aware of having ...
thoughts
of memories .
Like I 'd been invaded by something , and it was trying to take me over .
Something inside of me wouldn 't let that other thing take over , and I fought it .
I didn 't know where I was at first . And then it hit me .
I was outside , alone
unarmed .
( BANGING )
( GROWLING )
( DISTANT EXPLOSION )
( BONE CRACKING )
( EXPLOSION )
( ALARM SOUNDING )
The back wall 's been breached .
Don 't worry , the back door 's locked and secured .
Let me in !
It 's me !
Shit ! It 's Melanie ! Open the door !
Looks like her to me .
Haven 't heard any of these things speak in English .
C 'mon , Williams , the tide 's high out here !
Gimme those keys .
Come on !
Is it you ?
Yes .
It 's me .
I had a glimpse of the Martians .
Of their minds , of what they want .
They won 't rest short of the destruction of any invading species .
As far as they 're concerned , we are the invaders .
BASHIRA : Something 's kicking out there .
( HORDE ROARING )
Shit , they made a battering ram !
All right , everybody to the rear of the jail .
Bashira , you and Jericho go and load up on detonators .
You 're the second line of defence .
So , we stay here ?
We hold them off as long as we can , then we fall back to the store room .
Y 'know soon as we kill one , what 's inside will come after us .
I know . So if one of us gets possessed ...
Leave ' em .
( HORDE ROARING )
( BATTERING RAM POUNDING )
Here we go . Party time !
( ROARING )
- I 'm out . - I 'm out .
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
Move ! Move ! Clear !
Clear !
( RASPING )
Stand clear !
- Clear ! - Get out !
( RASPING )
WILLIAMS : I got it ! BALLARD : Take them out back .
Better get outta here .
( GROWLING )
Come on !
- ( EXPLOSION ) - ( GROWLING )
( SCREAMING )
Come on !
Come on , let 's go !
Look for the train . See if you can get them on the radio .
Jericho , get this thing started .
Whitlock , unlock the gate !
BALLARD : Come on , hurry up !
The train 's sitting at the station .
Opposite the train , do you read ?
This is the train , where the hell have you been ?
Where the hell have you been ?
All right , Bashira , come down !
Wait for us . We 're on our way .
Let 's go ! Come on !
Get in !
( ROARING )
Get yourselves ready !
McSIMMS : Oh , my ...
Come on !
McSIMMS : Come on , let 's go ! Let 's go ! Let 's go !
- Okay . Go ! Go ! - ( HORDE ROARING )
What the hell happened to you ? We got trapped north of here .
I 'll get us outta here .
( TRAIN ACCELERATING )
We 've gotta go back .
Slow down outside of town , then come to a complete stop .
No way .
- I 'm giving you an order . - I don 't care . The answer 's " no " .
The answer 's " yes " !
Look , even if we get back to Chryse
those things will just keep coming .
We 've got a chance here .
We 've got a chance to stop this thing before it goes any further .
This is about one thing :
Dominion .
It 's not their planet anymore .
What about him ?
Isn 't it our job to take him back ?
Is he still a prisoner , or is he one of us ?
I can give a damn about saving this planet .
It seem like it 's been after me since the day I was born .
If I 'm gonna die , I 'm gonna die fighting ,
not running .
Hey , Whitlock , if we blew up the nuclear power station what would happen ?
I mean , there 'd be a huge explosion , right ?
No , not unless you retract the control rods and expose the core .
Then what ?
Well , then you 'd have a small atomic bomb going " boom . "
BALLARD : How small ?
I dunno , it 'd blow out a radius of a mile , maybe two .
Would it kill them ?
It 'd certainly destroy their human hosts , but as for them ...
Hell , I dunno .
Jericho , can you get us in ?
I can try .
BALLARD : The plan was simple .
Sergeant Jericho , the Science Officer and I jumped off the train
and headed towards the power plant .
The others stayed aboard the train as it backed into the station .
The idea was they 'd provide cover
and distract the Martians as we set the charges in the plant .
Then they 'd swing back , pick us up ,
and we 'd all get as far away as we could before the place blew .
Like I said , it was a simple plan .
The only problem was it didn 't work the way it was supposed to .
( TRAIN BREAKS )
- How you doin ' , Jericho ? - I 'm working on it .
Hurry up .
( GUN FIRE ) ( SCREAMING )
( DOOR UNLOCKING )
We gotta remove the water jacket and destroy the containment shell .
Okay , so where do I put the dynamite ?
( EXPLOSIONS )
Officer to the train , they spotted us . Get your as back here now !
( LEADER SHOUTING IN MARTIAN )
Yeah ?
( GHOST SPIRIT RUSHING )
Argh !
Let 's go !
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
We gotta get outta here fast , the blast radius could be up to two miles .
- So , what 's that mean ? - It means step on it .
( MUFFLED BANGING )
Stay here and keep it full throttle .
- What are you gonna do ? - Lighten our load .
I think there 's some more dynamite in the rear car .
( HIGH-PITCH SQUEAK )
Williams ?
( GROWLING )
( DETONATOR BEEPS )
( ROARING )
See you later , you big motherfucker !
( SCREAMING )
( DOOR OPENING )
You okay ?
Say your prayers .
( INSTRUMENTS BLEEP )
I didn 't know you was cut this deep .
Should 've taken care of this hours ago .
You do that like a pro .
Yeah . Me and my brother have been through lots of battles
ever since we was kids .
I never thought I 'd go to war with somebody like you .
I know when you get to Chryse , you 'll tell those people that I helped you .
And I wasn 't the cause of all this mess around here .
Cause I know they 're looking for somebody to blame .
I swear to you , Williams , as soon as I get back
I 'm gonna tell my superiors all about this fucked-up planet .
They 'll drop the charges as soon as they get the report .
Okay .
That ought to hold it .
When you get there , have somebody look at it .
I couldn 't get it perfect , so it might leave a scar .
I 'm getting a collection .
You 'll be all right .
- Comfortable ? - Yeah .
I 'll get you a blanket .
( HANDCUFFS CLICK )
What the hell are you doing ?
This is where I get off .
What are you talking about ?
Well be in Chryse soon . Can 't let you turn me in .
I can 't let you walk !
What you gonna do ? Fucking shoot me ?
Look , there 's nowhere to run .
Anywhere is better than hell .
Catch you later .
Yeah , right .
Shit .
And what happened to Williams ?
I don 't know . When I woke up , he was gone .
And you were handcuffed ?
He must have done it while I slept .
At that point I trusted him .
And that 's all you have to tell us ?
That 's all know .
INQUISITOR : All right , Lieutenant Ballard , I suggest you get some rest .
You 're dismissed .
Is our statement to the Cartel going to be that Mars is being overrun by ghosts ?
( GHOSTLY RASPING )
TANNOY : ( WOMAN 'S VOICE ) Attention all police personnel ,
report to your nearest station immediately for weapon assignment .
A security breach has occurred in the south quadrant .
This is a level 10 emergency .
All police personnel , report to your division sergeant for assignment .
All civilians personnel , evacuate the streets immediately .
Please remain indoors until further instructed .
( MUFFLED CRIES )
Come on !
Tide is up . Time to stay alive .
( MUFFLED EXPLOSION )
( MUFFLED GUNFIRE )
If you ever wanna come to the other side , you 'd make a hell of a crook .
You 'd make a hell of a cop .
Nah !
- Let 's just kick some ass . - It 's what we do best .
( COCKING GUNS )
SUBTITLES BY POWERHOUSE FILMS LTD